<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013 Antti Järvinen <classified-ads.questions@katiska.org> -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>classified_ads.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPLv2</project_license>
  <name>Classified ads</name>
  <summary>Internet messaging system</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Viestinvälitysjärjestelmä Internettiä varten</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Classified ads is an attempt to re-produce parts of the functionality
      that went away when Usenet news ceased to exist. This attempt tries to
      fix the problem of disappearing news-servers so that there is no servers
      required and no service-providers needed for any operation ; 
      data storage is implemented inside client applications that
      users are running.  Features of the program currently include:
      <ul>
	<li>Posting of ads online. Ads have a category ; there are some pre-defined categories but more can be invented just by typing over the suggested categories.</li>
	<li>Replying to ads either in public or privately to operator.</li>
	<li>(Small-sized) binary attachments to posts.</li>
	<li>Providing basic data of operators - data that operator may enter himself, or leave blank.</li>
	<li>Basic searching of content based on words.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">
      Luokitellut ilmoitukset on järjestelmä julkisten ja yksityisten viestin
      välittämiseen internetin ylitse. Järjestelmä toistaa joitain toimintoja,
      jotka löytyvät myös usenet-news -järjestelmästä ja smtp-sähköpostista.
      Tämä ohjelma on suunniteltu toimimaan ilman palvelinjärjestelmää
      ja tästä syystä mitään sopimuksia minkään palveluntarjoajankaan
      kanssa ei tarvitse tehdä. Ohjelma ominaisuuksiin kuuluu mm. seuraavaa:
      <ul>
	<li>Ilmoitusten jättö kaikkien luettavaksi. Ilmoituksilla on kategoria,
	ohjelma toteuttaa muutamia kategorioita esivalintana, mutta käyttäjiä
	rohkaistaan keksimään uusia kategorioita.</li>
	<li>Ilmoituksiin vastaaminen joko julkisesti tai yksityisesti</li>
	<li>(Pienikokoiset) binääriliitteet viesteissä.</li>
	<li>Käyttäjän perutietojen välitys ; käyttäjä voi myös jättää itseään koskevat tiedot antamatta.</li>
	<li>Sanahakutoiminto julkisesta materiaalista.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://github.com/operatornormal/classified-ads/blob/master/doc/ads-search.png?raw=true</image>
      <caption>Search of classified ads by category</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://github.com/operatornormal/classified-ads/blob/master/doc/profilecomment.png?raw=true</image>
      <caption>Replying to operator in public comment</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">http://katiska.org/classified_ads/</url>
  <updatecontact>classified-ads.questions@katiska.org</updatecontact>
  <project_group></project_group>
</component>
